Zhengwei Bai

POSTGRADUATE STUDENT · JUNIOR SPECIALIST · MACHINE LEARNING · AUTONOMOUS DRIVING
Beijing Jiaotong University Technology Mansion, Haidian District, Beijing, China

Summary.

My research interests lie in motion planning, control and driving strategy for Connected and Automated Vehicles (CAVs). My current focus is to explore time-efficient, eco-friendly driving strategies for CAVs under heterogeneous traffic environment utilizing deep reinforcement learning (RL), which is also the core of my master thesis topic.

Education .

Beijing Jiaotong University

Beijing, China

M.S. in Transportation Information Engineering and Control

Sep. 2017 - Jul. 2020

GPA: 3.70 / 4.00; Awarded the graduate students first-class scholarship for two consecutive years.

Beijing Jiaotong University

Beijing, China

Sep. 2013 - Jun. 2017

B.E. in Electronic Information and Engineering

• GPA: 3.61 / 4.00; Awarded the outstanding graduates in Beijing Jiaotong University.

Experience_

Machine Learning Based Eco-driving Approach -- CE-CERT, University of California, Riverside.

California, United States

Visiting Scholar - Junior Specialist with Dr.Peng Hao

June. 2019 - Present

- · Design and Develop a Unity-based reinforcement learning simulator: signalized intersection scenario with CAVs and human-driven vehicles.
- Design a time-efficient and eco-friendly driving approach for CAVs by utilizing vision perception and V2I communication.

Swarm-intelligent Vehicle Control Theory and Test Verification under i-VICS.

Beijing, China

Project Researcher with Prof.Wei Shangguan & Prof.Baigen Cai

Sep. 2018 - PRESENT

- Working on the cooperative vehicle control methods and driving-behavior planning strategy.
- Proposed a cooperative driving strategy to achieve better time-efficient driving performance for multi-vehicles.
- Working on the evaluation framework for the test verification of the system.

Machine Learning Based CAVs Control and Driving Strategy under Heterogeneous Traffic.

Beijing, China

Project Researcher with Prof.Wei Shangguan & Prof.Baigen Cai

Oct. 2017 - PRESENT

- Proposed a deep neural network called spatiotemporal LSTM to generalize the steering angle output by fitting in the raw image data.
- Proposed a deep Reinforcement Learning (deep RL) based high-level driving behavior decision-making algorithm.
- Developed a simulation environment based on the Unity3D Engine for the training and testing processes of the deep RL algorithm.

Intelligent Transportation Information Management System (ITIMS) -- Siemens Ltd.

Zhuhai, China

Software Engineer with Dr.Dakai Yang

Jun. 2018 - Oct. 2018

- · Designed and Developed Five Software Modules of the ITIMS including bus, taxi, intersection, traffic signal, and flow detection modules.
- Developed several high-reliable multi-source data APIs which connect to the Traffic Police Department in Zhuhai.
- · Management and maintenance overall service infrastructure utilizing remote controller, Oracle & Mysql database.

Sangtian Island Autopilot Test Site Construction Proposal (Winning bid) -- Siemens Ltd.

Suzhou, China

Proposal Author with Dr.Dakai Yang

Jul. 2018 - Aug. 2018

- Analyze the equipment layout requirements (such as video perception, V2X communication, geomagnetic sensors, etc.) of the test site.
- Designed the automatic driving test scenarios basing on the site characteristics (such as the car-flowing scenario, overtaking scenario, obstacles recognition, etc).
- Wrote the most part (over 80%) of the proposal (20134 words in total) and made an oral presentation to the local transportation department.

High-speed Railway Based BeiDou Fusion Positioning Performance Test

Shenyang, China

Software Engineer with Dr.Debiao Lu

May. 2018 - Jun. 2018

- Test the performance of the GPS/BeiDou/IMU fusion positioning under high-speed motion scenario using SPAN, UB380 recorder.
- · Continuous testing on the Beijing-Zhangjiakou Railway (On the CR400 Train) for 7 days, 10 hours a day.

Field Strength Test System (FST) -- China Railway Urumqi Railway Administration Group Co.,Ltd

Urumqi, China

Software Engineer with Prof.Wei Shangguan

Sep. 2016 - Jun. 2017

- Design and developed a MFC framework based windows software (about 15,000 lines of C++ code) for the novel wireless FST system.
- Developed and tested the hardware system (collecting and packaging the sensor data such as ODO, GPS and TAX) of the FST system.
- · Testing the whole FST system between Urumqi railway station and Akesu railway station (2018km in total).

Publications & Ongoing Papers

Z. Bai, B. Cai, W. ShangGuan and L. Chai, "Deep Learning Based Motion Planning For Autonomous Vehicle Using Spatiotemporal LSTM Network," 2018 Chinese Automation Congress (CAC), Xi'an, China, 2018, pp. 1610-1614.

CAC2018

100+ Reads on ReaserchGate Oct. 2018

• proposed a deep learning based control modal (named as spatiotemporal LSTM network), which is able to generate a real-time steering angle planning based on raw image input.

Z. Bai, B. Cai, W. Shangguan and L. Chai, "Deep Reinforcement Learning Based High-level Driving Behavior Decision-making Model in Heterogeneous Traffic", arXiv:1902.05772v2

CCC2019

1 citation on Google Scholar

Jan. 2019

• Proposed a deep reinforcement learning-based method that can generate the high-level driving policy to make the CAV driving through a heterogeneous dense traffic flow at a higher speed with less lane change.

Z. Bai, P. Hao, M. Barth, W. Shangguan, B.Cai, "An Eco-driving Approach for Connected and Automated Vehicle under Signalized Intersection"

Ongoing

Preparing for Transportation Research Board

Present

Proposed a CAV control framework which combined conventional rule-based methods and reinforcement learning method. The ego-vehicle
can go through a intersection faster and save more energy (compared with some baselines).

Z. Bai, W. Shangguan, B.Cai, "Cooperative Driving Strategy for Connected and Autonomous Vehicles in Dense Traffic: A Deep Reinforcement Learning Approach."

Ongoing

Preparing for a journal paper

Present

· Proposed a cooperative high-level driving behavior decision-making methods so that the multi-CAVs can drive more time-efficiently.

Z.Bai, Design and Implementation of Novel Wireless Field Strength Test System

Undergraduate Thesis

Outstanding Undergraduate Graduation Project Thesis

May. 2017

• Designed a novel wireless filed strength test system and implemented in China Railway Urumqi Railway Station.

Presentation_

The 2018 Chinese Automatic Congress Session: Unmanned Control System

Xi'an, China

Dec 2018

Oral Presentation

• Introduced our working on deep learning based motion planning for autonomous vehicle.

Suzhou Transportation Department: The Integrated Solution for Autopilot Test Site

Suzhou, China

Jul. 2018

• Introduced the integrated solution for Sangtian Island Autopilot Test Site Construction Proposal.

Skills.

Programming Python: Application of Machine Learning Algorithms

C/C++: Application of the embedded systems & MFC software development
 C#: Application of the Unity-ML Based Simulation Environment Development
 Java: Application of a spring framework based Java EE project (Siemens: ITIMS)

HTML/CSS/Javascript: Application of the Personal Website development

Embedded Systems STM32: Application of the Novel CTCS (Chinese Train Control System) simulation system

C51/MSP430: Application of the Beijing Electronic Design Competition

Machine Learning Tensorflow: Application of most recent project (deep RL network).

Keras: Application of deep learning network construction (Spatiotemporal LSTM Network).

Languages TOEFL Reading 28, Listening 27, Speaking 23, Writing 23, Total 101

GRE Verbal Reasoning 153, Quantitative Reasoning 167, Analytical Writing 3.5

Honors & Awards

Scholarships

2018 **Graduate students first-class scholarship**, Beijing Jiaotong University

2015 **China National Scholarship**, (top 1%), Ministry of Education of the People's Republic of China

2015 **Excellent Student Cadre Sholarship**, (top 3%), Beijing Jiaotong University

Beijing, China

Beijing, China

Competitions

2018 2nd Prize, (top 10%), "BJTU Huiguang Cup" Graduate Academic Culture Festival Essay Competition
 2016 1st Prize, (top 1%), "Nokia Cup" Innovation Competition Final
 2016 2nd Prize, Beijing Electronic Design Competition Final
 2016 Beijing, China
 2016 Beijing, China

Misc_

Conference reviewer, Chinese Control Conference 2019, Chinses Automation Congress 2018

Deputy Director, the College Youth League Committee, BJTU

Student Secretary, the School League general branch, BJTU

Volunteer, the 2014 APEC Youth Program

Fall 2014 - Spring 2015 Fall 2015 - Spring 2016 Nov. 2014